you're playing pretty good but you're
kind of confused
which hand to use on the forehand
sometimes like using two hands and then
you go back to one hand so on the
forehand side which is everything on
this side to the right of you that's a
forehand you're gonna do it with one
hand
okay let me show you first how you're
gonna hold the racquet so the best way
to do it is just put your racket on the
ground like this
put it on the ground and then with your
hands you're gonna grab the racket like
this you're gonna put your hand right on
top of the racket
and pick it up when you hit the ball you
see how your hand is underneath the
racket all right and now it's going to
be a lot easier to go up with the
racquet like this
okay so go ahead and stand right here
i'm going to feed you a few balls and
now all i want you to do is just
position here stand right here on the on
the service line you know what
everything's called like this do you
know what the lines are called okay so
this is the service line
okay the one in the back is baseline
okay all right so right now we're going
to be on the service line and i put your
racket
right along the service line like this
you're just going to imagine making
contact don't let go of the racket hold
it back up a little bit
so this is going to be your contact okay
so now i'm going to drop a ball in front
of you and you're just going to finish
the stroke from the contact
to your left shoulder like this let me
show you you're going to start here
like this and then you're going to go to
the shoulder this way so when you're
done look when you're done your elbow is
going to be pointing towards the other
side like that so you're going to go
from the contact
to the left shoulder elbow is going to
point straight forward so go back and
you stand right here
one hand though remember forehand is one
hand okay not two hands you go in front
and just hit it from there
okay make sure you don't take too big of
a swing okay start kind of small you
want to get that ball
inside the court this is the most
important thing
beautiful job there it is do it again
okay you see you're taking the racket a
little too far back yeah do a little bit
less you start from here
hit it
nice very nice
do it again
put your racket in front where the ball
is
be a little bit more open towards the
ball so you're not so sideways okay
again
do another one
good
nice
very nice another one don't take the
racket see as soon as you start going
back you lose control so i want you to
just get a good feeling for the ball so
you're going to start as close to the
contact as possible so it's the contact
here i want you to start very close to
the contact when you start going back
all the way here
keep holding the racket you're going to
get disconnected from the ball it's
going to be very
difficult to control it so you start
here and just think about what's going
to happen from the contact to the finish
okay
there it is and see how you're making
pretty much all the shots right now
beautiful job
look you're making
everything that was like four in a row
here keep going
it's easy right
okay you miss i i jinxed you do it again
put this one away
come again
good beautiful job
what do you think
i like it it feels good right it seems
so much
easier easy right yeah yeah
so in your mind you're intuitive though
you know you just feel like you have to
like you don't have to just right now
just focus on the ball is the most
important thing and then you're going to
just think about the contact and you're
going to start at the contact and then
once you feel the ball on your racket
just finish it off like this to your
shoulder so now let's go i'm going to go
on the other side i'm gonna feed you the
ball you do the same thing okay
good
nice you start yeah start
that's okay start from the contact
good
wow look at this
are you sure you're a beginner
that was really really good now we're
going to go to the baseline i'm going to
hit one further back okay
now obviously you're going to have to
swing a little bit faster okay because
otherwise like a little bit stronger
otherwise the ball is not going to make
it very far you know so from here you
can accelerate a little bit more but
don't change anything
good and again you start from the ball
okay try again
good
good job just keep accelerating
and again
another one
okay remember start from the ball
sometimes you kind of get excited a
little bit you start
you start swinging a little too fast so
you have to the most important thing is
control yeah you have to control the
ball make sure it's going in
and then the other stuff power and all
that stuff we're going to go later
come again
good wow that's a really nice shot yeah
i like the sound this one the sound is
very sound it's very important
that was really good sound if you hit it
right it's gonna make the perfect sound
good try again
okay again it's going a little too far
like this when you start taking it too
far back
you know what's happening actually
without you even noticing there's
already intuitive elements of the stroke
so when you start here you're starting
here and i tell you accelerate you
number one wait longer and then you
actually do end up taking the racket
back without even noticing
you know but when you conscious which is
a very good thing that's how you're
supposed to do a backswing you're not
supposed to think about it but when you
go back here too early and you take it
back and and now the swing is too big
and you lose control and you also are
disconnected from the contact so
remember the most important thing is the
contact that you're that you have a good
control over the ball in the very
beginning
and the best way to do that is you just
kind of like
mentally the mental image of you
starting with the racket here gives you
a good sense where you're going to meet
the ball
and it makes the contact a lot easier so
right now when you're playing just
kind of put your racket in front and
then wait for the ball there
like right there
no it's fine they did pretty good yeah
do it again
nice
and another one
good and actually you are already taking
the racket back without even noticing
you started here look holder hold the
racket and the racket still went like
this which is sufficient that's all you
need okay
do a couple more and i'm going to go on
the other side
wow
again
it's unbelievable
so good so how was the forehand it was
pretty easy right it felt comfortable
makes sense now the difficult thing
about doing a backhand is you can't use
the same grip okay because remember go
ahead go ahead and find your forehand
grip again
remember remember how you found it let
me see how you find it you put the
racket flat like that and you pick it up
okay so this is your forehand now
remember if you were to hit a ball
on this side of your body your backhand
side you see what would happen is see
how the racket is open here yeah
everything will fly up into the sky
yeah but you can see how when you bend
it here your wrist bends
so you have to use a different grip okay
i'm going to show you how to do it so
now remember we had the racket like this
on the forehand
now we're going to put the racket like
this like neutral and i'll put your
right hand right on top of the racket
right yep like you're shaking somebody's
hand like that
okay put your thumb around put your
thumb your thumb your right thumb around
the racket the same way put your left
hand on top
and now make sure that the hands are not
overlapping okay make sure there's space
there okay good this is your backhand
grip okay we're gonna do the same thing
we're going to start in front but now we
want to be sideways we don't want to be
open anymore so you're going to be
facing this way
you stand right here
you face me face me put your feet
parallel to each other like this
all right and now you're going to start
in front i'm going to drop the ball and
you're going to go
up so that your left
elbow is pointing forward you see that
so i'll show you from this side so i'm
going to be sideways i meet the ball
here like this and now my left elbow is
pointing forward like that okay you see
and there's a little bit of upper body
rotation so you don't want to be stay
sideways and play like this you want to
rotate with the shot a little bit okay
the feet don't worry about the feet
right now later on you will move the
feet but right now just focus on the
actual stroke okay
and go up get the elbows up
it's very important that your
non-dominant elbow comes through at the
end that you're pointing with a
non-dominant elbow towards the target
when you're done which is the left one
left one exactly so it goes like this
like this this is going to be an
indicator that you're rotating a little
bit
good
now if you can hit it away from the
camera i'll be very thankful
which is i'm asking for a lot because i
know you're just starting with backhands
but i was close it's all right
i'm willing to take the risk because
this is an important important angle to
catch
good and again go ahead and rotate all
the way
i'm afraid of hitting okay i'm gonna do
one more and i'll move it but you see
the one one mistake that a lot of
players do when they hit a backhand that
the dominant elbow gets kind of
overwhelmed by the stroke and ends up
getting tucked in like this so it's
important that you go here that
non-dominant elbow has to go up okay
okay one more
much better and do it again
both of them are going up that's why i
put the camera this way so that you can
see uh that you can see what the elbow
is supposed to look like beautiful job
okay let's go to the baseline start
there
a little bit more
come and a little bit more with that
with that elbow look
you ever play golf
i tried it's kind of like a golf swing
where you you don't want to like go like
this you want to go like this bring the
whole system around like this so your
your elbow here go ahead and finish the
swing finish the swing
yeah i'm not i'm far away it's okay
i want yes that's it see this elbow
needs to point like towards the back
fence
yeah that's a full swing
so you want that you remember we're not
we're gonna minimize what happens in the
back over here but we're going to
maximize what happens after contact
okay so it's very important that we go
from contact to the finish
there it is
beautiful backhand wow
how's the sound you're liking the sound
on my back oh you're hitting yourself
that's good actually
that means that you're finishing the
correct way i always hit myself on the
back too and one more last one
very nice job
awesome
nice
good
yeah
so those back ends were pretty good yeah
all right so now you did forehand and
back and you did a really really good
job for a beginner i'm very very
impressed but now we're going to take it
one step further i'm going to have you
hit forehands and backhands and one
thing about this is that you shouldn't
do this with the same grip
and i'll tell you why because the longer
you do it with one grip so in other
words you're hitting forehand like this
backing like this your hand will get
used to that grip and eventually you'll
have to change it it's going to be very
difficult so i always recommend to
beginners that you find the correct grip
right away so forehand has to be hit
with a forehand grip backhand has to be
hit with a backhand grip and that's what
i want you to do next i want you to hit
one forehand and then a backhand and
you're going to be changing your grip in
between okay all right go ahead and go
in the middle of the baseline go right
there in the middle and go in what's
called the ready position basically it's
going to be an athletic position where
you're going to be waiting for the
incoming ball yeah and here you can wait
either in a backhand grip or a forehand
grip you will figure this out on your
own what your preference is maybe you
like forehands better maybe you like
backhands better but for now let's just
wait in the backhand grip and i go in a
ready position like this
and now i want to teach you real quick
the sequence of the stroke so when you
are waiting like this you're going to be
looking on the other side and the ball
is going to be coming to you and as soon
as you see the ball coming to your
forehand for example you're going to
make a turn to your forehand side so
you're going to go like this you're
going to turn
like that and the reason why now you can
run normal to the ball right okay
otherwise you'll be like running through
the ball sideways like this
that'd be weird right yeah now in
addition to turning you're also gonna
change your grip so you're gonna be
going from the backhand grip to the
forehand grip and turning at the same
time and the mechanism of changing your
grip you're actually going to be doing
this with your left hand so the right
hand is going to be loose and you're
going to turn the grip with your left
hand like this
can you do that for me a couple of times
there it is you turn and change the grip
there it is
there it is okay you don't have to let
go of the fingers you just kind of
loosen the hand and the grip will turn
you actually want to feel the grip on
your fingers so you know where you are
you're going to feel the bevels on the
grip
turn the body change the grip
wow
all right now on the backhand
if you're going to weight in the backing
grip you really don't have to do
anything you don't have to change
anything so go into ready position right
there in the middle ready position and
all you have to do is as soon as you see
the ball coming towards your left you
just turn towards the backhand side and
you hit the ball like we practiced
before now remember you want to be
sideways right so you don't want to be
open you can turn your body sideways on
the backhand
okay you're too open you know what i
mean by that
you're too you come into the ball and
you're like this you're open i want you
to be sideways like this come
on okay
yes do it again just like that
there it is
and come
beautiful shot nice
okay we'll do one more thing okay
go there right there in the baseline yes
and now actually you're gonna have to
change the grip so go into ready
position
and
no it's fine
and now you're gonna get a forehand so
you'll have to do the sequencing you'll
have to turn to the forehand side change
your grip hit a forehand come back to
the middle and then you're gonna go back
to your backhand grip and then hit a
backhand okay forehand
good back to the middle
ready position
change your grip
there you go backhand backhand
okay back to the middle
all right change your grip again and
turn
forehand good back to the middle change
your grip
backhand
so even though you're a beginner i feel
like your strokes are looking really
really nice sometimes when you start
from scratch you can build the right
mechanics right away you don't have to
change any bad muscle memory so you're
doing really good i will do a racket tap
all right actually you know what let me
take a look at your serve you know how
to serve
sir
all right let's check yeah you know
where to serve where to aim yeah you
have to aim in that little box over
there yeah okay
that was bad i'll do it again
try another one
okay
oh it's okay it's all right
well the first thing you're doing wrong
is you're kind of facing the court so
you're kind of open here you don't want
to be like that you want to face me when
you're serving you're going to be
sideways so go ahead and move this move
this foot back
there you go like a little bit more
there you go and now another thing you
have to start with a backhand grip
remember the backhand grip let go of the
left hand you're going to put your
racket in what's called the trophy
position okay you know what it's called
trophy because every tennis trophy
there's a person standing like this you
know on the trophy so this is called the
trophy position so you're gonna start
here and now you're going to take the
ball
in your left hand don't go back yet stay
on this side this is a left grip but
with one hand one hand
your backhand good and now you're gonna
take the ball look straighten the arm
but put the arm aligned with my racket
here your left arm
down down by your left pocket okay put
your racket in the trophy position
okay
i'm gonna set the racket don't move it
like this and now you're gonna put the
hand here like this
turn it the other way around turn your
hand
like this and now you're gonna toss the
ball up here toss it let go let go this
ball is gonna go here and you're gonna
hit it
here we go okay go again
okay you don't have to bend your knees
and then go up with your knees stay
straight and just go look you go here
toss it up and hit it like that trophy
with the racket trophy
right yeah this way
not bad at all now if you can throw the
ball a little bit more in front it'd be
even better okay
in front meaning here in front is here
like that open your hand like this go
here
take the ball
put in a trophy toss it in front
it's not bad
do it again
come on
see if you start going from the bottom
now you're doing a full swing it's going
to go it's going to be very difficult so
i want you to start halfway bend the
elbow a little bit bend so behind
like this yeah a little bit behind oh
yeah yeah
toss it up
okay you threw it a little too far let
me show you it's like you want to hit it
go ahead and stand there
you want to hit it somewhere around here
like this
all right
this
like a robot later on it's going to not
look like a robot it's going to look
really smooth
oh my god look at that serve
so that's the basics of the serve i
don't want you to do anything else you
already got the stance
you have the grip you're going to start
halfway and you're going to work on the
toss
and that's it for now we're gonna build
okay from here on all right do a racket
tap
very good very good
you